# Kinza Khan

# Graphic Designer

Address Islamabad, Pakistan, 44000

Phone 033-356-48055

E-mail kinza.khan1988@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/kinza-khan-3144bb222/

Skilled Graphic Artist specializing in Graphic Design . Highly artistic, talent for developing unique custom artwork , Innovative approach to idea and concept development , always on-task and fluent in Photoshop, Illustrator , InDesign and Corel Draw. Consistently creates skilled, clear and brand-specific designs.

### Skills

Logo design	● ● ● ● ● Excellent
Illustration	●●●● Excellent
Graphic design	●●●● Excellent
Magazine Layouts	●●●● Excellent
Package Design	●●●● Excellent
Stationary	●●●● Excellent
Flyer	●●●● Excellent
Brochure	●●●● Excellent

### Work History

2018-02 - Current

## Graphic Designer

Punjab Group Of Colleges, Islamabad, Federal

- · Designed books of Nursery Rhymes for Allied Pre Schools.
- · Created hard and soft copies of files to protect information.
- · Designed clear, engaging graphic communications for print and online use.
- · Supported company branding efforts with logos, stationery and cohesive social media imagery and graphics.

- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Developed creative design for print materials, brochures, banners and signs.

#### 2015-08 - 2017-11

#### Fine Arts Teacher

Institute Of Mentally Handicapped Children, Lahore, Punjab

- Created learning environment that encouraged fine arts appreciation.
- Identified students' creative needs and collaborated with other staff for fine arts development.
- Held afterschool meetings and rehearsals in preparation for shows.
- Evaluated and graded students' class work, performances, projects, assignments and papers.
- Met with parents to resolve conflicting educational priorities and issues.
- Attended department meetings and collaborated with other fine arts teachers.
- Gathered display materials and distributed programs for shows and performances.

#### 2013-01 - 2014-05

#### Fine Arts Teacher

Allied Schools, Lahore, Punjab

- Created learning environment that encouraged fine arts appreciation.
- Held afterschool meetings and rehearsals in preparation for shows.
- Evaluated and graded students' class work, performances, projects, assignments and papers.
- Engaged in corrective and disciplinary action when appropriate.
- Attended department meetings and collaborated with other fine arts teachers.
- Scheduled shows and performances in accordance with school calendar.
- Gathered display materials and distributed programs for shows and performances.
- Sponsored student fine arts clubs, attending club meetings and events.
- Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.

#### 2011-08 - 2011-09

### Graphic Designer

Allied Schools, Lahore, Punjab

· Designed books of Nursery Rhymes for Allied Pre - Schools.

#### 2011-07 - 2011-08

### Graphic Design Intern

Manhattan Communication (Pvt) Limited, Lahore, Punjab

- $\cdot$  Created and managed computer-generated image design projects to minimize cost and meet production deadlines.
- $\cdot$  Photographed new products, clipped images, and cataloged final versions in library of graphics assets.
- · Drove client exposure by aligning design work with brand image and values.
- · Managed various graphic design assignments for web design and marketing projects.

#### 2009-12 - 2010-02

### Graphic Design Intern

Royal Media Network (PVT) LTD, Lahore, Punjab

· Devised and updated customers' branding logos, social media graphics, and print

materials.

- · Retouched and manipulated images to meet professional standards.
- $\cdot$  Developed marketing and communication brochures, direct mail collateral, and event posters.
- $\cdot$  Worked under direction of senior project managers and graphics design team members on collaborative objectives.
- · Created hard and soft copies of files to protect information.
- · Designed clear, engaging graphic communications for print and online use.
- · Supported company branding efforts with logos, stationery and cohesive social media imagery and graphics.

### Education

2011-01 - 2012-12	Master of Fine Arts: Graphic Design	

University of The Punjab College of Art & Design - Lahore (Pakistan)

2006-05 - 2010-10 Bachelor of Fine Arts: Graphic Design

University of The Punjab College of Art & Design - Lahore (Pakistan)

2014-06 - 2015-08 Bachelors in Education: Education

University of Education - Lahore (Pakistan)

2004-09 - 2006-08 F.A (Humanities): Humanities

Wahdat College For Women - Lahore (Pakistan)

2002-09 - 2004-06 Matric: Computer

Govt . Comprehensive Girls High School - Lahore (Pakistan)

### Software

Soliware		
	Adobe Photoshop	●●●● Excellent
	Adobe Illustrator	Excellent
	Adobe InDesign	Excellent
	Corel Draw	Excellent
	MS Word	Excellent

# Languages

English Excellent
Urdu

Excellent

# Certifications

2021-10 Certified [Graphic Designer, Freelancer], [Digiskills online training programme] - [Oct

2021-Dec 2021]

# *Interests*

Sketching

Painting

Listening Music

Baking

Eating fast food